AYUSH ASHISH SHIRSAT

161 Bigelow Street, Unit #2, Brighton, MA 02135 (+1) 857-928-2698 ayushshirsat96@gmail.com **LinkedIn:** https://www.linkedin.com/in/ayush-shirsat **Portfolio:** https://ayush-shirsat.github.io

Software Engineer with experience in designing Machine Learning algorithms that translate complex data into intuitive insights and visualizations. Can work independently and in cross-functional teams to provide analytical reports and data models to help organizations make critical strategic decisions.

EDUCATION

Boston University College of Engineering

Sep 2018 - May 2020

Master of Science in Electrical and Computer Engineering (Specialization in Data Analytics)

Birla Institute of Technology & Science (BITS), Pilani - Dubai Campus

Aug 2014 - May 2018

Bachelor of Engineering (Honours) in Electronics & Communication Engineering

Springboard

Jan 2021 - Present

Certification - Machine Learning Engineering Career Track

EXPERIENCE

Blue Cross and Blue Shield of Florida, Jacksonville - Software Engineer On Contract via M3BI, LLC

Aug 2020 - Present

- Implemented Logistic Regression and Random Forest in Python to detect potential customer defection with 73% precision to help company retain customers and save around \$500 Mil in revenue/year
- Built Time Series Models using Seasonal-ARIMA and Holt-Winter to forecast New Health Insurance Enrollments for the year 2021
- Performed data sanity checks on SQL Server tables and used that data to build dashboards in PowerBI and Tableau
- Designed web-based dashboards using Flask, Plotly, HTML, CSS and JavaScript

City of Haverhill, Haverhill - Data Science Consultant

Sep 2019 - Dec 2019

- Worked via BU Spark of Boston University to communicate with client Director of Public works, Haverhill, MA
- Performed exploratory data analysis using Python libraries like Seaborn, Matplotlib and Pandas to provide insights into 311 non-emergency service data
- Predicted time taken to resolve user complaints by performing regression using SVM

Boston University, Boston - Grading Teaching Assistant

Sep 2019 - Dec 2019

- Graded Assignments and tutored a class of 50 students for course Computational Linear Algebra
- Helped students to complete their coding assignments using MATLAB

Mahindra & Mahindra Ltd, Mumbai - IT Intern

Jun 2016 - Aug 2016

- Helped the company design network infrastructure on a new floor in the building and tested its simulation using Cisco Packet Tracer
- Presented a technical report on Blue Coat proxy and its utility in IT environment

SOFTWARE SKILLS

LANGUAGES: Python, SQL, HTML/CSS

LIBRARIES: NumPy, Pandas, Scikit-learn, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Plotly, TensorFlow, Keras, PyTorch, OpenCV, PySpark **SOFTWARE/TOOLS:** Git & GitHub, SQL Server, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, MATLAB, Jupyter Notebooks, Microsoft Excel, Power BI, Tableau, Windows and Linux

PROJECTS

Pneumonia Detection

Jan 2021 - Present

- Built models like Masked-RCNN and ChexNet using TensorFlow in Python to detect and localize Pneumonia in Chest X-ray images
- Built a Flask Application for users to upload Chest X-ray images and deployed it using AWS EC2
- The application returns the diagnosis of Pneumonia and its location using bounding boxes based on opacity in chest images

Analysing EfficientNets in Grading Diabetic Retinopathy

Jan 2020 - May 2020

- Implemented a family of state-of-the-art CNN models called EfficientNets using TensorFlow in Python to detect severity of Diabetic Retinopathy
- Achieved Quadratic Weighted Kappa score of 85.6% in grading Retinopathy which surpassed human score of 78%

Twitter Analysis

Sep 2018 - Dec 2018

- Streamed tweets using Tweepy API in Python to extract tweets with images
- Used Google Cloud Vision API to caption the images and stored top 5 media descriptions
- Built databases in MySQL and MongoDB to store Tweet, User ID, media file and media description